It was a productive first week for the
Patriots in free agency, but how's it
going to affect their draft plans?
That's what we're going to break down
here on Patriots Draft Countdown. With
the 31st pick, the New England Patriots.
Welcome everybody to Patriots Draft
Countdown presented by Bud Light. Easy
to drink, easy to enjoy. Bud Light is
the official beer sponsor of the New
England Patriots. And this is our first
instudio show of the new season, guys.
Exciting. We're back on the draft draft
mode, I guess you would call it. So,
first things we're going to start off
with is we talked, you know, after the
Super Bowl, all kinds of needs that the
team might have. Now, they've gone out
in free agency and and really they've
kind of swapped one for one. Guys left,
they brought another guy in to fill
that. So, you know, not a whole lot of
movement upwards, but it feels like
they've kind of built a dam. I guess
they're not hemorrhaging any players,
but Ev, I want to start with you. Just
overall, what's your big takeaway of how
this free agency period is going to
affect the draft? What's the headline
for you? Yeah, I think you kind of
nailed it there as it sort of was, you
know, let's tread water in free agency
and set up a big draft. And I think
specifically in a lot of different
positions, they didn't resign any of
their in-house free agents, which I find
pretty fascinating coming off a team
that won 14 games and made the Super
Bowl. But when I look at it at the spots
of players that they let walk, you know,
Austin Hooper at tight end, Galani Tvai
and Jack Gibbons out at linebacker,
Anthony Jennings and Kavon Chason out at
edge rusher. These are all positions
that I kind of expect to be on their
radar in the draft, you know, just
adding one more with Vidian Low at
offensive tackle. So, uh, the idea to me
it looks like is let's create
opportunity and let's create potential
roles for us to go out and draft players
at tight end, at offensive tackle, at
edge rusher, at linebacker. Uh, that,
you know, you have pathways for these
guys to contribute and make the roster
because if you just bring everybody
back, it's going to be hard to find
competition and spots for 11 draft
picks. you know, maybe they don't make
all those picks, but it looks to me like
they're kind of setting up for opening
some pathways for some of these younger
guys to step into some roles.
>> T just what stood out to you most about
the free agent class? I mean, was there
one particular signing that that you saw
that you weren't expecting or just, you
know, something that that surprised you
maybe?
>> The one that stood out was Romeo Dobs.
Just I know the receiver uh positions in
a question here. AJ Brown, we've been
hearing about that. You let Stefan Diggs
go. Dobs is a very good NFL player. is
not like the sexy number one wide
receiver, but he is a guy that will like
make an instant impact. So, just kind of
interested to see if he's going to be
your one for the season or what are we
going to do with that. So, that's a guy
who sticks out to me.
>> The blocking tight ends and fullbacks
not for me. Not for me. We like that,
right? It's real. It's real football
there.
>> I guess the edge rushers, but no,
receiver. It's always receiver messing
with you.
>> No, you mentioned receivers and you know
later we've got almost a half hour long
segment where we break down a lot of the
wide receivers here. It's always a
position we love to watch and to
fantasize about drafting that elusive
number one. But what was interesting to
me is you rattled off those positions.
And when we were in India at the
combine, we heard, you know, from Elliot
Wolf, Mike Frabel mentioned things like
the tight end depth is great in this
class. The defensive ends, you know,
this is a great edge class, which is a
need that, you know, that they admit.
Um, those are two that jump right to the
forefront of mind. I also could say
linebacker. We've seen, you know,
there's a good offthe-ball linebacker
class. Is it an accident that some of
these signings that they did did feel
like placeholders at positions that are
kind of filled with talented players in
this draft?
>> No. And I I think that what you feel a
little bit more optimistic about because
I I think when I rattle all those things
off, people are like, "Wow, that's kind
of a lot, right, to leave all this to
the draft." But it's not starting
players like they're not expecting them
to draft a tackle in the second or third
round that's going to have to start as a
rookie. They're expecting to draft a
tackle in the second round or third
round that's going to sit behind Will
Campbell and Morgan Moses and learn for
a year. So, they they've done a nice job
of being able to kind of set up a
pipeline here of, okay, we still have
Hunter Henry on the roster. So, if we
draft a tight end on day two or early
day three, that player is now competing
to be the backup tight end and not the
starting tight end. So, you don't put as
much pressure on the rookie. And I think
that that's sort of where they've gotten
themselves into trouble in recent years
is that they're expecting Jaylen Pulk or
Kaden Wallace or one of those players to
kind of be a savior and come in and fix
a position of glaring need. I don't see
that with this roster. I see them being
able to kind of set up here for the
future instead.
>> Now T, you and Chris Cassidy coming up.
You broke down a bunch of mock drafts.
Just, you know, not to spoil the
segment, but give me a headline of what
did you guys see from the mock drafts
that out there? I know there's a lot of
edge. That's that's what we've been
talking about. Is that what you saw?
>> It's a lot of edge. There's a bit of
surprise of offensive line, but I think
edge it's really just you can't really
go wrong that late in the draft. There's
so many options. There's no correct
position. So, you want to get a guy who
can have a not immediate impact, but
solid impact. And it really seems like
edge is where that's the opportunity at
the 31st pick.
>> Yeah. I mean, the opportunity of to have
like a third guy and you know, maybe you
have your your top two guys with Jones
and and hopefully Harold Landry is able
to come back and, you know, take that
down. But then if you have a guy like
let's just say Cashas Howell who's a guy
that I think everybody looks at like he
kind of plays like Mike Rabel likes um
you know you plug him in not the
pressure to come in and play three downs
right out of out of the out of the out
of the gate but the ability to come in
work in as a pass rusher see what he can
do get his feet wet maybe somebody gets
hurt and he has to get thrust into it.
That sounds like the plan even like at a
position like tight end too. Yeah, I
think that's the interesting part about
Edge in particular, and I'd also say the
same maybe a little bit about wide
receiver, but at Edge specifically, are
they looking for a guy that has a
certain skill set to contribute in 26?
Are they really thinking about this is
going to be a starter for us down the
line? Because there's guys in this edge
class that are kind of pass rush
specialists, like a Romelo Height, for
example, from Texas Tech. He's like 240
pounds, but he can really rush the
passer. But do I project that as a
player that's going to be a three down
player in the NFL? Probably not. He's
probably more a third down pass rush
type of role. There's the same sort of
thing, but on the other end of the
spectrum in terms of edge, you know,
guys that stuff the run and play the
edge like, you know, DDS from Penn
State, you know, big dude, kind of like
an Anthony Jennings type, or are they
trying to sort of, you know, split the
atom there and get a guy that they feel
like really has like three down starter
upside? So, I'm interested to see if
they're looking for more of a rotational
player or if they're looking for a guy
that they really feel like has a ceiling
of a every down player. Uh because, you
know, I I think Draymond Jones, when you
pay him that contract, is probably going
to play a ton. But like, is there a
scenario where, you know, maybe you
knock Harold Landry off the field for a
more dynamic edge rusher on third down?
Is that the type of guy that they're
looking for? So, it's a there's so many
options that it's kind of just a pick
your flavor thing of what exactly it is
that you're looking for. But, you know,
Cash's How Mezador you know, players
like that are guys that project as
full-time players in the league. Once
you get it past that, I think you're
kind of getting into he's really good at
this one thing. And it just depends on
which one thing they want to be really
good at.
>> All right. Well, we got a pack show for
you. We're going to have a bunch of pack
shows all spring breaking down all the
different position groups. Of course, we
start off with quarterback, wide
receiver, but first we got Batis and
Chris Cassidy going to break down the
trends in all the latest mock drafts.
What's up everybody? Welcome to the
Patriots Draft Countdown podcast. Matis
B here with Chris Cassidy.
>> How we doing
>> guys? It's the draft Chris. Patriots
reigning AFC champions. That being said,
>> not for the franchise, but for us, we're
in unfamiliar territory. The past two
years, Patriots are picking top five.
All right. Now, we're pick 31. That's
right. It's a little bit different. So,
what we're going to do here is go over
some mock drafts. We're going to do our
own. But right now, when you mock and
you're at pick 31, it's a bit of a
crapshoot. You can't really go wrong
with the position, but you want the
right player. So, Chris, as I run
through the Patriots mockdraft tracker
right now, the three consensus picks are
Zion Young,
>> TJ Parker, Casey, Conception. Yeah. So,
what are your thoughts on Let's go with
TJ Parker.
>> I I really like TJ Parker. I mean,
mention 11 and a half sacks. We were
talking about earlier, 11 and a half
sacks with Clemson this past season. I
mean, he's he's a stud off the edge, and
I think I really do believe the Patriots
are going to focus at that edge position
in this draft. I don't know if it's
going to be the first round or the
second round. Personal opinion, I think
it should be the first round, Matise.
Uh, but TJ Parker is a guy to keep an
eye on. Another guy that I really like
personally is a key messador from Miami.
Um, first round talent in my opinion. I
think there's a chance he could fall to
the Patriots. Uh, I've heard some rumors
he could be like early second round guy.
So, I mean, who knows? But, uh, I really
like Ake Meador uh, as well.
>> Yeah. I mean, Chris, so what you think
right now is the edge and we I mean,
listen, Kaleon, good season. He's not
back. Harold Landry is getting up there
in age. So, edge is a key position. I
have Zion Young like two picks on the
tracker said,
>> this guy's a bull. He's from Missouri.
He's a dog. I mean, he he's you watch
his tape and he's just blowing guys
over.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's a beast. And again, you
need a guy who can get to the
quarterback. But I think what the
Patriots lacked this past season was
>> somebody that could help in the run game
from the edge. Like you had these guys
that like uh Kavon had seven and a half
sacks past year. Don't quote me on that.
I'm pretty sure that's why. And I think
that's that's a good thing, but I still
think he he lacked a little bit of that
running game presence. And I think
that's where the Patriots need to keep
uh getting better at. And I think Zion
Young is a good person uh to fill that
role in a way. So, so Chris, edge
rusher, that's what you're thinking. For
me, my thing with a first round pick is
you need to hit the ground running. Like
we saw with Drake May, we saw Will
Cable, like they they're playing. You
need to be a starter. That being said, I
feel like we talk about this every year.
Patriots are also looking at some
receivers. I can't believe we're at this
again. And it's interesting because now
we're picking so late that for me
personally, like I'm not sure if I'm
taking a receiver there, but the name
that keeps coming up is Casey Conception
from Texas A&M.
>> Yeah. I mean, Casey, he's all around a
great receiver. He's he's a beast and uh
he's one of those guys he's going to
come in. He's fast. He can really play
the slot. You can put him outside if you
want to burn. Like put him where you
want. I kind of see him more inside as a
receiver. Um you know, Patriots could do
multiple different things, that sort of
situation.
>> I think he's going to go in top 15 with
these. I I do. I think Casey's going to
jump up in this draft. I think he's a
stud wide receiver. I think he's going
to show it uh kind of as the time
progressed leading up to the draft. And
I I really would it be a blessing if
Casey Conpsion was on the draft board at
31 for the Patriots? Yes. Do I think the
Patriots take him? Yes. I don't know if
that's a real life.
>> So, the mocks keep having him. But that
being said, Chris, in years past, you
got you got Ibuka, you got JSN. Like,
does does he fall in line with those
players? Is he of that caliber to you?
>> Yeah, I mean, he very well could be. Uh
I think people are just very high on him
this year. I think he's just he's the
name that's been following around the
draft uh sort of this whole off
seasonason. So, uh, again, I think he's
going to keep keep climbing the ranks
here in this draft. And, uh, it'll be
interesting to see if he's there at 31,
but
>> So, you hope he is?
>> Ideally, HE'D BE GREAT. IDEALLY, it'd be
great.
>> All right. So, Chris, like we're going
to keep doing this section. We're going
to do some of our own mocks, but right
now in our first section, you're on the
clock at 31. What are you doing?
>> I'm going edge. I think I think you need
to focus at that edge position. Um, you
know, like we talked about it, you lost
uh Kavon, you know, Harold, he's great
off the edge when fully healthy, but
he's a little little injuryprone in in
playoffs. So, you know, you need a
little bit of help there. You also you
have a guy in Harold who can help train
these young young edge rushers and kind
of grow their development a little bit.
And you brought in Draymond Jones from
the Ravens in free agency, another vet.
Like, these guys can help this young
edge rusher become the best version of
himself.
>> All right, cool. Chris, right now I'm
going to trade the pick, but we got
plenty more time to go over this. But we
talked about Casey Conception. Guys,
we're going to talk more about receivers
in the next section.
All right, we're kicking things off here
with quarterbacks and wide receivers.
Guys, I don't think we need to spend a
lot of time on the quarterback. Of
course, Paul, they signed Tommy Devito.
He's he's signed up. Josh Dobs with with
Drake May. We got the depth chart taken
care of. All right. So, if you're going
to look at this from a Patriots
perspective, then you probably um you're
probably set. You probably don't need uh
anymore. Now, if they decide to move on
from Dobs and they're looking for
another sort of developmental
quarterback in the draft, maybe a day
three pick. They have a bunch of day
three guys.
>> Um
I don't know if there's a lot here for
you uh necessarily. I I don't know where
Drew Aller is going to go, the kid out
of Penn State
>> who I do think has some tools. uh as
Evan Evan would call him tools.
>> Um but he has not really put it together
at the college level in terms of
refinement and consistency. But if you
could get him, you know, sometime, you
know, like I don't know, round four,
round five,
>> um you know, probably five.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> maybe that would be a guy that would
intrigue me. But most of the rest of
these guys, you know, Tailing Green,
>> you know, unbelievable combine, but not
really a quarterback.
>> Have anybody stands out like lower end
guys before we get into this? Yeah, I I
I mean I think Aller is probably going
to be a top 100 pick still.
>> So that's that's too high for me.
>> Maybe fourth round. Maybe he's he gets
into the fourth round. You mentioned
Taylor Green, I think the biggest thing
with him, and not to no disrespect cuz I
think he can play quarterback, but you
know, he comes in, you draft him, plays
quarterback at first, you test him out
there, if it doesn't work out there,
he's such an exceptional athlete. Like
is he a Terrell Prior type that can
maybe change positions and be a wide
receiver? I don't mean to do that. I
think it's disrespectful sometimes when
people do that, but it's just the
>> He's an exceptional athlete. No, no
doubt.
>> He's an exceptional athlete. No doubt.
Uh, now in terms of, you know, deeper
guys, I think what the question is is
that you're asking is, are you really
drafting somebody to be the backup, a
pure backup, like again, no disrespect,
Chase Daniel, right? Like are you
drafting someone Brian Hoyer that's
going to be the backup for the next 10
years or are you looking still for Joe
Milton who has a little bit more upside
and a little bit more of those traits? I
would say Tayen Green is probably more
in the Joe Milton category. You know, a
guy like Diego Pavia from Vanderbilt is
maybe more in I think this guy's going
to have a 10-year NFL career as a as a
backup quarterback. Uh, you know, I
think that's really where you're kind of
at with that class is are we at the
point now, which I think we probably are
with Drake May, that he's the starter
forever as long as he'll be a New
England Patriot as long as they can keep
him a New England Patriot. So, sounds
right. So, you might as well, you know,
look at a Cade Clubnick from Clemson or
Diego Pavia from Vanderbilt or one of
these guys that has a chance to be a
long-term backup.
>> All right. Well, let's let's jump into
the top two guys because T, I mean,
Fernando Mendoza probably going to be
the first overall pick. Good chance the
Patriots see him this year. uh you know
with the Raiders and then Tai Simpson
another guy who know probably first
rounder but more maybe more of a
developmental guy we know seems like the
Jets need a quarterback but let's just
start with Mendoza what a year national
championship Heisman I mean saw him at
the combine looks the part completely
under control he's going to be a good
player
>> yeah I just take him for the leadership
you know he's a big locker room guy uh
led that team really changed the culture
there with um their coach
>> Perks and Yeti
>> yeah probably going to be the Raiders
guy I think they're going to have to
deal with Something that's interesting
with Mendoza is I'd like to see where
you think he would have went last year
like with Cam Ward. I I just don't know.
I think
>> number one overall.
>> Yeah.
>> The Drake May draft is probably more of
a conversation between those three guys,
but I think we would have been having a
conversation of those four guys. Like I
think he would have been in the same
tier as Caleb Williams, Jaden Daniels,
and Drake May. Now, would he have had
the same exact college football season
if all those guys were in college
football still? And you know, would he
have been the Heisman Trophy winner? I I
guess maybe he would have had more
competition for something like that, but
if he had the same exact season he had
at Indiana last year, uh with that
class, he would have been the fourth
horseman there, you know, with with the
group. So, he's he's really good. He's
going to be a really good player, I
think, in the league.
>> Yeah. What do you think, Paul? The Tai
Simpson Alabama.
>> So, I think both of these guys are
underrated athletically. Uh I think um
Mendoza shows you that he's he's a
quarterback. He's not just sort of back
there throwing the ball. He can move
around and run when he's not going to
make a living doing that. Seven rushing
touchdowns um last year. And I think Tai
Simpson
is a little bit more of a projection
because he didn't first of all, he
didn't play as much. Um and if you look
at the first half of last season for
Alabama, and I think I said this to you,
Evan, during the course of the season,
at one point I was like, he's the best
quarterback in the country. Then all of
a sudden it kind of changed. um and he
didn't play as well in the second half
of the season. I think he got beat up a
little bit. I think he was dealing with
some injuries, but there's some there's
some skill there to work with. He has a
really really and I in my view an NFL
arm. Um you know, he's not like Drake
May or Josh Allen like howitzer or
anything like that, but I think he quote
unquote can make all the throws. I like
both of these guys. I like Mendoza a lot
more because there's been a lot more
production and consistency, but I
wouldn't sleep on Tai Simpson. I think
someone at the end of the first round,
one of these teams, I know people have
sort of dismissed this, but like I think
you'd make a ton of sense for a team
like the Rams who are going to need a
replacement for Stafford soon. You
completely take off the no possibility
of him having to play in year one unless
Stafford gets hurt. I think that's the
kind of development that could lead to
him having a successful career.
>> Yeah, I think the interesting thing you
said there about Tai Simpson, we can
talk about him as a player. I mean, I I
think his best attribute is probably uh
his ability to throw a touch and timing
to the intermediate deep part of the
field. You know, he throws those nice
catchable pillows, you know, that hit
guys in stride. You know, watching guys
like Jeremy Bernard, for example, who
we're going to talk about here in a
second with the wide receivers, you
know, he would run those crossing routes
and Tai Simpson would put it right on
him in stride. If you ask him to try to
drive the ball down the field,
especially outside the numbers, it gets
a little iffy. And there were times
where he's throwing the far hash and
he's trying to get the ball out outside
the numbers and receiver it's it's a you
know he's throwing skip passes you know
to his receivers like those are the
things that you worry a little bit with
him but I wanted more talk about what
you just mentioned the back half of the
first round. The Patriots are sitting
there at 31. We obviously know the
Patriots are not taking a quarterback at
31. So, is this a situation where
somebody at the top of the second round
might want to come up and grab Ty
Simpson before the night is out and the
Patriots might have a trade partner
there, a tradeback kind of candidate
situation? I think there are a handful
of teams that uh could be, you know, in
the market for a quarterback like Tai
Simpson that make some sense to come up
and get him, you know, from the second
round, top of the second round to come
back up to 31.
>> All right. Well, let's move on to wide
receiver because that's a position that
hey, we always need, right? We're always
looking for the number one wide
receiver. I think the interesting thing
now, of course, as we said at the top of
the show, is that they've now signed
Romeo Dobs, who seems to be a one forone
replacement for what Stefan Diggs, and
the search now continues for an outside
receiver. You know, of course, Kahan
Booty had a really good year, really
good hands, nice connection down the
field. So, I found myself over the last
few days kind of gravitating more
towards the outside guys. And I know
there's a different variety and and you
know, first I'll just rattle off the top
three names with Jordan Tyson, Carell
Tate, Mail Lemon. I feel like those guys
probably going to go above where the
Patriots are going to pick. I And I'm
going to go and I know I'm going to get
some push back on this one and I'm ready
for it, but Denzel Boston, I I can't I
know not a burner and we need speed and
that kind of thing. Uh but I just feel
like this guy is a stud and and how many
times do you have to take a chance on a
guy before you find one that even though
he doesn't have speed, his size and his
strength just overshadow that to me. big
powerful hands, you know, strong outside
presence, a number of different things,
um, that you can do with him. Maybe not
the breakaway speed, but return punts.
Um, you know, has a little bit of wiggle
to him. So, I would just kind of start
with him because I feel like he's in
that area of the late 20s. And I, you
know, we can talk about his speed and I
get why people might be afraid of him
plus the combination of Washington
Jaylen Poke/ he's kind of built like
Nikil Harry. So, that's kind of a
devastating combination.
>> I just figured you were talking about
>> it's kind of a double kind of a double
busting there. But as I was watching him
like I just I really gravitated towards
this guy. So I mean I'll let you guys
jump on on him or or T or somebody you
know one of the top guys you want to
talk.
>> I had Boston on my list and just he can
be high volume. I mean he led the team
with 62 receptions uh 881 yards just
different red zone threat. That's really
something the Patriots need but deuce
with the receivers. I think of the past
years we've had CD Lamb JSN Ibuka all
these people and like to me her being
available to us there's not really
anything like that. So, I've reached the
point with a first round receiver like I
want a name and I just nobody really
sticks out to me this year to be to be
worthy of the of our pick, which now
we're not picking mid top round. We're
picking at the end. That's just me
personally.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Should we just
>> There are clusters, right? There's
clusters of these guys and you know,
Denzel Boston, I think, is the one guy
that's kind of in this in between
cluster of probably a top 25 talent in
the class. There going to be concerns
about his athletic profile. He didn't
test at the combine. Usually not a good
sign. When a guy that has questions
about long speed, doesn't run a 40 in
Indianapolis, it's cuz he wants those
secret hand times to be at his proday
where we shave off 210 of a second, you
know, when we're getting them tweeted
out by Albert Brer or whatever it is.
So, uh, like that and that was not a
shot at Albert Brer. I took it as such.
>> But, uh, that that is the
>> that's the tough part. And I think what
you look at is side kind of the
justosition of a guy like Malachi Fields
from Notre Dame. He runs. He runs a 46.
Warning bells, right? Then Denzel Boston
doesn't run. So you still kind of have
this hope that maybe really the number
you're looking at for him is like, can
he run a low 45? If he can run somewhere
around like a 45 flat to a 453, and I
know the 40 everybody's like, "Oh, who
cares about the 40?" It's all about
thresholds and sort of just baselines,
right?
>> I do like I think when you watch him,
you watch highlights, he looks I think
he plays fast. That makes sense. Maybe
he doesn't have the measurables. Uh you
know, people have drawn the like the
puka sort of comparison with him. And I
can see why cuz I do think he play I
mean
>> maybe at the catch point I don't see him
as a puka baller. No, not after the
catch. But I think the things that you
see with him at the catch point, you
know,
>> I meant from a competitive standpoint.
>> Yeah. and and he's an exceptional
contested catch guy. You know, 10 out of
13 of his contested targets he caught.
That's a very high percentage of those.
Uh I think what he does well is he he
creates these little pockets for the
quarterback to put the ball up on a
platter. And when you have an accurate
Yeah. an an accurate downfield thrower
like Drake May where he can read it and
say, "Okay, I'm going to throw him open
on the back shoulder or I'm going to
high point him this time or I'm going to
lead him that this time or we're going
to throw him to the little bit to the
inside." And he can just use his body
positioning and he has incredible hands
and incredibly strong hands to just sort
of box out and win the ball at the catch
point. We call him a ball winner cuz he
just goes down field and just wins the
ball. Uh that all being said, speed,
separation ability, ability to beat
press man coverage, like these are all
profile concerns with a guy like Denzel
Boston. Yeah.
>> Well, let's kind of stay in this chunk
though because I mean we had really been
talking about Conpsion from Texas A&M,
Omar Cooper Jr. from Indiana. Say those
are kind of the other two guys that you
see kind of in that late first round. Uh
and I I mean I really liked Conpsion. I
thought he was explosive kind of guy. I
mean, but it feels a lot like he would
do the similar things that you just got
with Romeo Dobs. So, I don't if you guys
have any thoughts on those. I mean, Omar
Cooper Jr., a lot to like about him. He
seems like a dude to me.
>> I had Cooper um just very versatile.
He's not only going to play in the slot.
I keep mentioning high volume. He had 69
receptions, 937 yards. If we're taking a
receiver that early, I just I've been
hurt too many times. I just want
somebody who can
>> elevate the wide receiver room we have.
And I think he's one of the few people
that can do that.
>> Yeah, I think they're they're they're
the same but different. You know, Casey
Conpsion is a burner. Uh, really good
route runner, separates really well at
the top of the route. He has a lot of
these routes that you're going to see
going around Tik Tok and Twitter where
it's like, look how open this guy is
getting himself. The one concern that
you see with him are drops and the
ability to finish through contact. Like
those are two things that he struggled
with a little bit at college at the
college level. Omar Cooper Jr. a really
good athlete, another guy that's really
quick, fast, all those different types
of things. The one thing that I thought
about with him at Indiana when I was
watching him, he doesn't really run a
route tree right now. He's kind of just
running to space. They run a lot of
RPOS's, a lot of bubbles, a lot of, you
know, college type of schemes there at
Indiana. And Omar Cooper Jr. is just a
exceptional athlete. He's really strong
with the ball in his hands. Uh there
have been some comparisons, you know,
with him to some of those Rams receivers
over the years like a Robert Woods or
somebody like that that's just extremely
competitive. Uh, but I don't know if he
necessarily ran like a robust NFL route
tree where I can say this is exactly
going to translate. You're just kind of
hoping that the movement skills as a
whole translate. But both those guys are
right in this range like they're going
to be end of the first round uh, you
know, in the 20s maybe if the receivers
get pushed up, but I think that there's
a chance that one of them is there at
31.
>> I like both of them a lot. I agree with
your point, Mike. you know, Romeo Dobs
may have changed the profile of the guy
that the Patriots might be interested in
that high in the draft.
>> Yeah.
>> But I do like both of those guys a lot.
I agree with a lot of what the boys just
said. So, um I I'm curious to see what
you guys think of a bigger guy uh in in
Eldridge's guy um from Tennessee,
Brazil, Chris Brazzle. Um
>> now you're talking my language.
>> So, go ahead. Give the floor to you
then. I mean, so yeah, I mean,
>> I always am careful with comparisons
because you make these comparisons to
these like Hall of Fame caliber
receivers and you don't want to do that.
>> There's shades of it, right? Where like
you're talking about this guy that's
6'3, 6'4 that has this long striding
speed, uh, that is really, really good
at winning the ball again down the field
at the catch point, but is exceptionally
fast. And I think the one thing that you
looked at with him from, you know, an
outsiders perspective is just how fast
is exceptionally fast. He goes to the
combine and he runs in the high 43
threes. So like now you're really
talking about a guy that's got legit
vertical speed. He also has great size
and a great catch radius and I think he
catches the football really well. So
you're looking at somebody that I would
call an accuracy eraser where like if
you throw it a little high, if you throw
it a little low, you throw it a little
outside of him, he's got that radius
kind of like M. Holland to like go up
and catch the football and contort his
body and make those types of catches
while having legit burner deep level
speed. And so if you wanted to just kind
of print out in a 3D printer, a wide
receiver for Drake May, a guy with
exceptional downfield ball skills, deep
speed, size, contested catch ability,
the ability to go over the middle of the
field and win the football in traffic.
>> Did I just that that's the guy that you
would want to pair with a guy like
>> too. He's not like this, you know, he's
a big guy, but he's smooth and the
footwork um you know, the sideline stuff
I think he showed. I think you're right,
Ev about his versatility. He's not a
onetrick pony. I like the
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Just a little thin. I mean, you
know, he's I mean, he's thicker, but I
And look, I It's all personal
preference, and sometimes I I tend to
shy away from these guys. And I I rubber
stamp everything you just said. I just
think I tend to go more towards the
bigger, more physical guy. And maybe
that's a fault of mine, but easy to see
how he would fit in on this offense.
Just, you know, and again, you always
draw the comps of Taquon Thornton. That
was, you know, what they were looking
for that same thing. He's not that guy.
I agree. I mean, he's also, you know,
one of the captains. And
>> question I have this year as I look
through the players, Evan, where does
somebody like that rate like in the
round grade? Because you have like the
top three guys that are going to
>> So, I I think he's a pure second
rounder. Okay.
>> But I think that he's going to be a top
50 pick. And I, you know, just to the
Taekquin point real quick, like this guy
is
>> almost 2 in and 25 pounds heavier than
Taekwon Thorick. You know, Taekwon
Thornton coming out was was 180 pounds.
you know, this guy's 20 I think 205 uh
you know, right around there. Like this
is not the same thing. If there's any
concerns about Chris Brazzle in terms of
that all of this is that Tennessee
offense is super weird. What the way
they run their route tree is super
weird. They have these max splits where
like the guy is basically one step from
being out of bounds and he's like
running routes from all the way out
there in their spread and their air
raid. So like it it's more about Jaylen
Hyatt, Cedric Tilman, Dante Thornton,
like all these receivers that have come
through Tennessee that have not
translated to the NFL because at
Tennessee all they're doing asking them
to do is take off. Like just go down the
field and we'll hit you down there
somewhere. That's not going to you're
not going to be able to do just that in
the NFL. You're going to have to be able
to do a lot more.
>> Well, let's uh you know, let's move on.
Just open the floor to anybody's
favorites. I asked a couple you guys to
watch Josh Cameron from Baylor, uh,
who's a later round guy, but I just had
a lot of fun watching him. He wears 34.
He looks like a running back. He's
completely raw. Um, but one of those
guys where I pull him up and I start
watching like, who is this guy? I, you
know, I told Paul and T, I'm like,
"Watch this guy. Just tell me what you
think." I think we all reacted the same
way.
>> The first thing I thought of is like,
he's built like Antoine Bowman, which he
is. He's 61, 220.
>> He's sloppy. He's all over the place
running over people.
>> There's some players that just use their
build and he's one of them. which is
very exciting to watch. Um I was a big
fan when you showed this
>> team. I mean it's like you know late
round guy that maybe a developmental
kind of flyer but
>> you know maybe a day three guy. Um I he
looks like a running back. I think it's
he's he's a couple of guys like that in
this class. Uh the the guy from Navy uh
Eli I I
>> I'll take your word.
>> Yeah. Uh he's
uh you know the guy from Navy is if Bill
Bich was still here we would be talking
about him. Oh in the second round at
Nazium. you know, this is a running back
slash receiver who runs routes out of
the backfield like a wide receiver that
went to Navy that played multiple
positions. Like this is, you know, an
old school Patriot right through and
through. But we got to go back to day
two cuz we're we're glossing over like
the whole
on day two. So just
>> Jeremy Bernard.
>> Yeah, Jeremy Bernard is an interesting
player. I think he's more probably in
the Romeo Dobs profile.
>> Say that's my problem. I have a bunch of
guys that I looked at like that.
>> Yeah. So, we'll get to him in a second.
I I I think the other guy that we need
to talk about, and I was busting bars
balls about this guy yesterday cuz he
kept on talking to me about it all
college football season. Then in late
November, November 22nd, the last game
that Louisville played in co in the
regular season, Chris Bell blows out his
knee and tears his ACL. So, Chris Bell
would have been a first round pick if he
had a healthy knee.
>> And he does not. And the one argument
that I was making, it was kind of funny
because we flip-flopped like this is Bar
Sky and now he's kind of reser reserved
about it because of the knee. The
Patriots to me are a team that needs
ceiling at the wide receiver position.
They need to hit big like they need
they're not
>> I don't know if we're necessarily
looking for just another guy to add into
the mix at this point at wide receiver.
And are they in a position where let's
say Chris Bell's there in the second or
third round because of the knee injury
where you're just going to kind of hope
that the knee fixes itself and we're all
good because I I think there's a world
now that we live in where like these
injuries are not career debilitating
anymore. You know, guys bounce back from
ACL's all the time. He's a 22-year-old
kid, you know, like hopefully he bounces
back from it. So, I think Chris Bell is
a really interesting name as someone
that you might be getting a round or two
later than you were probably going to be
getting him at. We'd be talking about
him at 31 if he was healthy. Uh, so
that's an interesting one to me as well.
I know that there's a lot of people that
are into Jacobe Lane from USC2. I've
heard he's not exactly Vrabel's cup of
tea, you know, not necessarily the a
effort and finish, big- time play
strength kind of player, but big another
huge catch radius kind of guy. Great
>> side of the field, run down the field
and catch the ball. Like that's how I
saw him do. But
>> very good in the red zone. Uh, you know,
can run the slant, can run a go, can run
red zone routes, can post up on guys.
He's got some really great highlight
reel catches on his film as well like
that. Then you kind of get into, you
know, the Ted Hurst of it all and uh,
you know, th those types of players that
went to Georgia State. You know, again,
we're talking about guys that are size
specimens. You know, that people that
fit that sort of mold of having uh, you
know, the the size we're kind of talking
about with Chris Brazzle, you know, that
sort of profile. And, uh, you know, that
that's how we kind of go. and then you
know the kid from North Dakota State
like we're we're kind of just going down
that line of you know second third
fourth round profile of like a
traditional downfield X receiver
>> but I feel like when you get later in
the rounds that's not the player the
Patriots need to be honest like I think
they need the big X guy which is I just
I think we've done enough of the
mid-round receiver.
>> Yeah I mean I think we're all coming out
to the guys with the size that can play
on the outside probably the best fit.
Yeah, I think that is the best fit which
is too bad because I think there's a lot
of productive guys that are like in you
know you know Zachariah Brown, you know,
uh Branch, sorry, and uh Brennan
Thompson like they got like productive
guys. I but I agree with everything you
guys are saying. I not necessarily sure
they need another one of those.
>> Yeah, even looking at guys like uh you
know Dion Burks from Oklahoma, Skyler
Bell from Yukon, little guys, you know,
the little slots that I think we would
have been more enamored with.
>> Feel like I don't know if that's if
that's Drake's kind of sauce. Really the
question I think we're asking is what's
the best fit on the outside and how much
of a you know chance do you how much of
a swing
>> do you take any other guys that we
haven't really talked about you know
Bernard pretty balanced guy I mean he
>> Kim and Sarat are both really good
players I think Bernard is probably a
little bit more explosive a little bit
more of an athlete than Serat I love
Serat I think Serat is Jacobe Myers 2.0
know, like I don't think he's going to
wow you w with his athleticism or his
speed, but he's crafty. He knows how to
get open. He's got good hands. He's got
good size to him. So, he's not really
like a pure, you know, Welker Edelman
slot. He's got a little bit more of a
6'2 profile to him. Uh he's really
interesting player. You know, I I don't
know again like those guys, Bernard
Serat, um even Antonio Williams, he's
like more of a pure slot receiver from
Clemson.
>> We yak for that guy, Antonio Williams.
He's those types of guys. I think you
know Antonio Williams in no in a Tom
Brady Josh McDaniels offense would eat
in the slot.
>> 28 career receptions. Insanely
productive.
>> I don't know if that's necessarily what
they're looking for right now. Uh but
Bernard and Sarat are another guys that
I think are just really consistent, good
route runners. Uh get know how to play
the game, know how to run routes, uh
know how to play the game. Uh that
that's pretty much it, you know, for day
two. I mentioned Ted Hurst, you know,
Bryce Lance from North Dakota State. Uh
those are the types of guys that if
you're looking for again like athletic
traits and upside and, you know, just
physical size, speed, ability, uh that
would be what you're banking on. And
then you kind of get into the later
rounds with, you know, like Jeff
Caldwell from Cincinnati who is another
like this
day three guy version of this, right?
Like you know, the fifth or sixth round
version of this. Um, I have one more
that I'll just throw out there and then
if you guys have any more, but uh, the
one guy I would just mention as like a
late round guy is Lewis Bond from Boston
College. We know that Mike Vrabel and
Bill O'Brien have a relationship. Uh,
I'm sure that they'll see him in a
couple weeks at BC's Proday right down
the street. If the Patriots are planning
on moving on from Pop Douglas after this
season at some point, Lewis Bond is
profiles as a very similar type of
player to Pop Douglas. And I just
wonder, you know, Pop has one more year
on his contract. It's not a huge role
that they're asking him to play to begin
with. You know, Lewis Bond probably
there in the fifth or sixth round or
something like that as sort of a one
forone replacement uh for Pop if it
comes to that. So that that's I I think
the list that you're sort of looking at
uh as of right now, unless I missed
anybody.
>> I got late round guy. This is late round
guy.
>> Late round guy. This is one of our what
six six round picks. I got Kaden uh Ween
from Iowa. just big return guy as Marcus
Jones gets, you know, a bit more
important on defense. Not sure if you
want to risk him with the punt returns
that much. This guy set the school
record for punt returns, two kickoffs.
>> That's a good call, TE, cuz some of
these guys that we're talking about day
three possibilities do have uh extensive
punt return experience and you that's
Marcus Jones is the best punt returner
that I've seen.
>> Yeah. And it's
>> But you might wonder if they're going to
continue to do that.
>> Yeah. It's risky. I mean, if you need
him in a clutch situation like with the
Jets a couple years ago, you do that.
But he's just you need him now at
defense. But we gen keep an eye out for
him. Training camp guy.
>> Anybody else? Paul, you want to take us
home? Any
>> No, you guys got all the all the guys I
mentioned. I like uh Jeremy Bernard in
Serat, you know, just cuz they're a
little bit bigger than those pure slot
guys. Um they're not going to wow you
with athleticism and burst, but um a lot
of uh physical traits that you I mean,
not the least of which is their
physicality. Uh, Sarat is definitely one
of those guys that that wins wins all
the battles.
>> So, Boston, Bell, and Brazil. Is that is
that three guys that that kind of, you
know, intrigue different types?
>> Cooper, too.
>> Yeah. I
>> I think Brazil is the guy to me that
makes the most sense. I just don't know
how you make it make sense in terms of
where you're going to draft him.
>> Uh, 31 feels a little It feels a little
bit rich. Uh, if they did it, I wouldn't
kill him for it because the profile is
just so good and you can see how it fits
perfectly, you know? Not that I It's
kind of like how we were talking about
Alec Pearson free agency. Like, is he a
true star elite receiver? Probably not.
But the fit with Drake May set of
skills.
>> Yeah. Is just so enticing. And I think
Brazil fits that similar thing. And I
I'm not opposed to taking a third round
flyer on Bell and just betting on the
fact that his knee is going to check
out. Like I we just saw Stfan Diggs do
this. Like he just came off an ACL and
was basically the same guy. I don't
think that this is 20 years ago when
those injuries are just career ending or
he's never the same guy as he was
before. I I know the Notre Dame people
are going to kill us about Malachi
Fields and and my my distaste for that
kind of receiver, but
>> move him to side. I mean, like once you
run a 46, you're off my list. I'm sorry.
>> All right. Well, that's going to do it
for this episode of Patriots Draft
Countdown presented by Bud Light. We're
just getting started, guys. The draft
fast approaching. Got you covered all
spring long.